$2,620 per square foot divided by 91
years,
multiplied by 99 years equals $2,850
per square foot. Example, JadeScape.
$2,850
per square foot plus 7 % equals 3,000
that
tender grew 15 bits. Average today,
$2,508 per
square foot. High of 2. If we are new
here, I'm Coach Edmund.
I check every big launch with a system
we built called the REI
method. The same checks we run with
clients before selection day.
So they walk in with a plan instead of a
failing ground. I've checked
before that I just exited one of my new
launch unit.
It grew $375,000 in under 4 years. And
I've been looking out for
my family's next property since with a
budget around $3.5 million to
$3.8 million. So the $1,178
per square foot per plot ratio. Upper
1,000 MRT is just 2 minutes
walk. McRitchie is next door. Ai Tong
School is within 1km and
that matters for the school ballot.
Preview is estimated to be on the 3rd
October and launch will be on the
17th October. They are not confirmed and
there is no official price
list yet. Analysts guessed about $2,800
to $3,000
per square foot. So every price you hear
today is
a very critical decision making process.
And if you do this incorrectly,
you may be getting stuck in your
property for 2 and 3 bedrooms
into this area. And we don't know the
split yet.
You'll be the first one to know when I
do and with similar
location.
And we
want to have a breakdown of how many
units are there in each
project.
So we break it down from 2, 3, 4. Some
of them will have one bedroom. So we
of break them down. Thomson impression,
Thomson grand,
Thomson tree as well as jade skip.
So this is the second layer of research
we do to
see the supply in that estate.
So one thing we know that jade skip they
actually only built
55 % of the 2 and 3 bedroom.
Only 55%. And that's about and they
built
this amount 265 3 bedroom.
Okay,
we'll come back to the numbers shortly.
Okay, why these are all important.
And because of this 265 units,
this potentially is also the reason why
jade skip prices went up a
lot. Okay, if you all have been seeing
people
who bought jade skip and then they make
a lot of money,
they're very happy. But we must
understand what drives that and wrote
what I call the COVID bonus. The entire
market jumped more than
30%.
It will not necessarily perform the
same. So be realistic
about that. The second project to look
at are more residences,
372 units just up the road completed
this year.
His land was bought in 2021 for a lot
more for bits. That could be a
huge deciding factor in how Thomson
reserve plays out. Stay all the way to
video as I will breaking down why this
is an important factor to
choose which unit type will have a
higher chance of success for Thomson
reserve.
One fact before anyone gets carried
away. If you're just looking at
JadeScape skins and assuming Thomson
reserve with its the
three years later,
note that straightscape launched before
COVID.
Effectively buyers are paying $3,017 per
square foot
instead of $2,620 per square foot.
Fact number 5.
One important factor before buying into
any area.
Study the supply of each unit type.
Because that determines your
future demand for your own unit. It's
very easy to say
JadeScape made money so any size can
buy. Please don't be
so fast. Here's the breakdown.
I pulled the younger projects within
1km. I deny year lease holds only
to keep the comparison accurate.
Thomson impressions,
TOP 2019, 288 units,
101 bedrooms,
72 2 bedrooms,
106 3 bedrooms including 3 plus 17, 445
units,
61 1 bedrooms,
168 2 beds,
185 3 beds exact type.
Every project, new launch or resale
eventually becomes a
so you can research for the project for
weeks. You can pick your
right objective
but you may not be able to have a clear
direction on
how this breakdown is going to be.
So remember if you are looking at this
project as a U
versus a capital growth, it's a totally
different matrix.
So let's say if Thomson reserve they
split 50 -50
between the 2 and 3 bed rooms.
Then the number of units should stay
similar because both are kind of similar
right 50 -50 % but this is scenario 1
only.
So if you're asking a admin why is this
important? If I buy, if it's a 50 -50 it
means I got more chance to buy a 2
bedroom or I can choose a 3 bedroom.
Nothing wrong.
You see that's why I'm more kiasu and
kiasi right I always plan different
scenarios right but the risk is if the
scenario is they
build more 2 bed rooms and if you are
somebody who's looking to invest
chances are you are going to buy a 2
bedroom regardless right
then you need to understand this.
If there is going to be a supply of 853
units into
this region we're talking about 1600 2
bed rooms
and generally 2 bed rooms are for what?
For investment and what are
you going to do with that?
You're going to rent it out.
Is that area going to have so much
demand to rent from
you?
So you can see why we think too much
right sometimes yeah
we think too much okay but at the same
time is they
I'm only talking about this region for
rental okay so
are they going to be a huge
injection of population into Thomson
area
to be able to rent from you? Who is
going to rent from you in future if
we're talking about a huge supply of 2
bed I mean the
tenants okay there must be a real supply
and demand situation
if not it's just nice to have
but then when you are the landlord
you're going to struggle yourself
everybody is fighting for that one
tenant and you know what happens
when you're fighting for that one tenant
your price will definitely be
adjusted.
Then of course then you will say that oh
if then maybe I don't buy 2 bed
room I go and buy 3 bedroom okay in this
situation it seems the 3 bed
rooms would be lesser supply which makes
it more favorable
okay but again if it's 3 bedroom then we
also have to
have to agree
that's where your affordability comes in
whether should you go for a bigger 3 bed
room compact 3 bedroom whether that
price makes sense or not
for you to enter if it's they do a more
3 bedroom okay
if they do a more 3 bedroom then we're
talking about 1600 units
into the market for 3 bed rooms okay
then in this case then you need to
kind of look into how the developer is
going to price
okay if let's say they are doing this
because it's only
853 units they may price their 3 bed
rooms a little bit more higher
because they want to get more profit
margin right so this
is more on the mentality of how
developers think right because generally
make their money from 2 bed rooms not
saying make but because they are able to
sell it fast so they can kind of clear
out their 2 bed rooms as quickly as
possible and that forms their 30 % of
their margin to kind of
take a loan so if they are
going to build lesser and they're going
to increase their 3 bed rooms then
chances are their 3 bed rooms are not
going to be cheap at all so what do
all think the maximum number of units
will have
would it be the 2 bed rooms to have the
majority of the 84 %
or the 3 bed rooms will have the
majority of the 84 % comment
below what's your thought arrows if
Thomson reserve splits roughly 50 -50
between 2 and 3 bed rooms that's fair
against the 8
that's fair against the areas existing
supply both
types stay considerable but if it leans
heavily on the
2 bed rooms I'll be much more careful
about a future oversupply
of that therefore 4 bedroom people were
willing to pay
up to 4 million of course 4 bed rooms in
the entire district 20 okay so that's
something I don't know if you ask me if
you are able to afford
go for the bigger units okay whether
it's the bigger 3 4 bed
room if you can afford
5 bedroom I will not go for big 3
big 4 okay 4
is exciting because
they only have that little units for
for the entire development right and in
the entire district 20
or shall I say Thomson area right
there's a lack of supply for 4 bed rooms
so that one is really dependent on your
log whether you are able to get so
I believe 4 bed rooms will also be very
sellable in Thomson reserve
because of lack of supply and generally
those who
buy 4 bed rooms are going to be they
want to buy for own stay they're going
stay long right but that's where you are
able to kind of ride on the
overtime of the different market cycles
exist the 2
minutes Emirati comes with 5 print that
walk is only true for the nearest blocks
the furthest one at another 7 minutes no
interchange no
more built -in so your stack choice here
matters far more than the
brochure suggests 2 units in the same
project can have completely different
resale stories the
launch price make micro factors that
makes this unit very
exciting especially in this location
where 4 bedrooms
are under supply so let us take a look
at the whole entire
layout first coming in from
one caution if you're buying for
investment I don't believe you
should be just holding for 4 years
that's too short
hold it at least for a midterm okay 5 to
6 years will be a good gauge for your
property to kind of mature and see
the next site already include the future
of the adjusted resale numbers the
$2,800 to $3,000 per square foot we
worked out then
buyers on day one are paying tomorrow's
price today it's not that
Thomson reserve is no good it's just
that I'm kind of worried that he'll be a
little overhyped because why because a
very crowded
ballot right it just proves the demand
easy
but it doesn't prove that whether this
property the value and
many of times the problems come during
the ballot
but before the time we need to kind of
plan
the hit so that we know what are the
prices
what's your situation what's your
objective
and then when you come to the selection
day
what is our situation what are the
prices that we should be
doing and after that you we are not
going to just let go
right we're going to continue our
journey so that whether we're renting it
or later on we're going to help you to
sell so that you can move forward and
kind of all right put in the comment all
right it can reach out to us we will
help you to do a comparison to determine
which four bedrooms or even
which five bedrooms is much more ideal
for you but looking at this
that's literally what the link below is
for